<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>OGF-38: Issues</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/ogf-38/issues.atom?query_id="/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/ogf-38/issues?query_id="/>
  <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/</id>
  <updated>2013-06-26T12:26:58-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Grid Forum</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://www.redmine.org/">
Redmine  </generator>
  <entry>
    <title>sessions #92 (submitted): OGF and Related Standards in XSEDE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/92"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/92</id>
    <updated>2013-06-26T12:26:58-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Alan Sill</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Many elements of software designed for use in the XSEDE project are based on OGF and other available formal specifications and standards. This session will review the use of OGF standards in XSEDE, explain the development and creation of OGF documents in the informational, community practice, experimental, proposed and full recommendation categories, and detail the process for creation and contribution to the standards that are related to the XSEDE project. OGF's role in promoting best practices and cooperative use of standards from other standards development organizations will also be detailed and reviewed. The session will conclude with an open-mike discussion on future standards development needs for XSEDE&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>sessions #87 (submitted): BoF: MOOC in computer/computational science education.</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/87"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/87</id>
    <updated>2013-06-12T06:44:07-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Redmine Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;A massive open online course (MOOC) is an online course aimed at large-scale interactive participation and open access via the web. In addition to traditional course materials such as videos, readings, and problem sets, MOOCs provide interactive user forums that help build a community for the students, professors, and TAs. MOOCs are a recent development in distance education.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This BoF will discuss relevance and options of MOOCs for an CS curriculum, and will investigate the potential role of OGF.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>sessions #86 (submitted): OGSA-BES</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/86"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/issues/86</id>
    <updated>2013-06-05T06:42:19-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Redmine Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;OGSA-BES session to discuss and vote upon the Activity Endpoint Profile.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
