<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Public Comments Archive: #78 EMI Execution Service</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/13.atom"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/13"/>
  <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/</id>
  <updated>2013-06-17T09:36:50-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Grid Forum</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://www.redmine.org/">
Redmine  </generator>
  <entry>
    <title>#78 EMI Execution Service: Document is in public comment until August 20th, 2013</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/13/topics/14"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/13/topics/14</id>
    <updated>2013-06-17T09:36:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Redmine Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://redmine.ogf.org/attachments/74/PGI-EMI-ES-Spec_v2-0.pdf" class="external"&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/13/topics/new" class="external"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment Here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The Production Grid Infrastructure (PGI) working group works on a well-defined set of standard profiles, and&lt;br /&gt;additional standard specifications if needed, for job and data management that are aligned with a Grid&lt;br /&gt;security and information model that addresses the needs of production Grid infrastructures. These needs&lt;br /&gt;have been identified in various international endeavors and are in many cases based on lessons learned&lt;br /&gt;obtained from the numerous activities in the Grid Interoperation Now (GIN) community group. Therefore, PGI&lt;br /&gt;can be considered as a spin-off activity of the GIN group in order to feed back any experience of using early&lt;br /&gt;versions of open standards (e.g. BES, JSDL, SRM, GLUE2, UR, etc.) in Grid production setups to improve&lt;br /&gt;the standards wherever possible. This particular document captures the a reasonable stable draft of the&lt;br /&gt;execution service specification of the European Middleware Initiative (EMI) that has been created based on&lt;br /&gt;many identified PGI concepts. A complementary implementation of this draft specification is provided by the&lt;br /&gt;EMI project including adoptions in ARC, gLite, and UNICORE. The goal of this document is to capture&lt;br /&gt;community practice and to have a foundation for a set of important standard specification updates to be&lt;br /&gt;addressed by the PGI set of profiles and/or specifications of the corresponding related groups (e.g. BES,&lt;br /&gt;JSDL, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
