<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Public Comments Archive: #166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/21.atom"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/21"/>
  <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/</id>
  <updated>2015-02-10T11:08:48-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Grid Forum</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://www.redmine.org/">
Redmine  </generator>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: Closed - RE: Comments on document</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419?r=426#message-426"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419?r=426#message-426</id>
    <updated>2015-02-10T11:08:48-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Beckerle</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;These comments have been incorporated, and the latest version is now up on the DFDL Workgroup Documents/Current folder.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: CLOSED - was RE: New DFDL bitOrder is needed for binary format whose...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/421?r=422#message-422"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/421?r=422#message-422</id>
    <updated>2014-12-02T11:48:33-05:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Beckerle</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for your supporting comments. No followup required.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: New DFDL bitOrder is needed for binary format whose field order is s...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/421"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/421</id>
    <updated>2014-10-29T18:50:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>russ hawkins</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am responsible for parsing and unparsing binary formats whose specification lists the fields from right to left, and whose fields are rarely on byte boundaries, often many fields being contained within a single byte.   Although within a given field the MSBit is on the left, within a given byte and across byte boundaries the first field to be parsed is to the right (toward the LSBit side) of the second field to parse, and so forth from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In a data stream for this protocol (serial or socket) the content bytes are presented least-significant byte first, which approximates the first to last field order but the approximation is insufficient.  The inverted intra-byte and cross-byte field order presents a problem - it is not parsable with normal MSB first interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This problem is much different from and not solvable by a simple endian byte order specification.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The new 'bitOrder=leastSignificantBitFirst' enhancement addresses this need.   Without the 'LSB first' feature we cannot parse this type of content with DFDL processors and must resort to custom solutions.  There are several legacy formats whose specifications follow this reverse-field-order presentation whose parse and unparse will be facilitated by the new feature.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: Issue 236 - RE: Comments on document</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419?r=420#message-420"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419?r=420#message-420</id>
    <updated>2014-10-28T13:05:38-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Beckerle</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Thank you this was obviously a thorough reading of the document. &lt;br /&gt;We will incorporate the things you mention above.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Issue to track fixing this &lt;a class="external" href="http://redmine.ogf.org/issues/236"&gt;http://redmine.ogf.org/issues/236&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: Comments on document</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/419</id>
    <updated>2014-10-21T07:39:16-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Jens Jensen</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Mostly read up to section 3.  Any questions about the comments, please feel free to contact me: jens.jensen &amp;lt;at&amp;gt; stfc.ac.uk&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;p.4&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;"A bit can always be unambiguously identified as the $2^n$-bit" &lt;br /&gt;- did you mean "[..] for some $n$", or did you mean "The $n$th bit&lt;br /&gt;[..]"&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Your bits now number 1..8 instead of 0..7&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A picture might help, er, picture the adjacency: showing the bits in&lt;br /&gt;the byte followed by the bits in the next byte.  In fact the stuff in&lt;br /&gt;section 2.2 is good, so I would insert a reference here saying "see&lt;br /&gt;section 2.2 for the illustration" or something.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Nitpick: is it mandated how the alignment (up to a byte) is to be&lt;br /&gt;filled?  Should they always be zero bits?&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Section 2.1&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Nitpick: there is only one combination left, bigEndian with&lt;br /&gt;leastSignificantBitFirst.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;2.2&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I like the coloured XML - nice.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;2.5.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The example makes it clear enough but one can nitpick the text:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Technically the AlignmentFill doesn't occupy the most (resp least)&lt;br /&gt;significant bits, since there might be a bit field in the most (resp&lt;br /&gt;least) significant part - as indeed there is in your example.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;"so the &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; AlignmentFill" - there could be more than one&lt;br /&gt;AlignmentFill in a single byte!&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;comma after "dfdl:binaryNumberRep='binary'"&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;3.1, 3.2.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Some "Error! Reference source not found."&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#166 - DFDLv.1 Experience-3: Document is in public comment until November 17th, 2014</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/418"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/418</id>
    <updated>2014-09-16T13:07:52-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Redmine Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Links&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://redmine.ogf.org/attachments/148/gwde-dfdl-experience-3-v1.1.pdf" class="external"&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/21/topics/new" class="external"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment Here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This document provides experience information to the OGF community on the original Data Format Description Language (DFDL) 1.0 specification (GFD-P-R.174).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Modeling a MIL-STD-2045 header in DFDL v1.0 is not possible without the addition of new capabilities for specifying bit order and non-standard encodings. There are many related military-standard binary data formats which are similar, and so cannot be modeled in DFDL.This document describes the new properties and property values that are required to successfully model this format.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;All resulting errata have been incorporated into a revised Data Format Description Language (DFDL) 1.0 specification (GFD-P-R.207) which obsoletes GFD-P-R.174.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
