<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Public Comments Archive: #65 Grid Certificate Profile </title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/8.atom"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/projects/editor-pubcomarchive/boards/8"/>
  <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/</id>
  <updated>2021-11-05T06:58:01-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Open Grid Forum</name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://www.redmine.org/">
Redmine  </generator>
  <entry>
    <title>#65 Grid Certificate Profile : RE: Comments on Grid Certificate Profile</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7?r=557#message-557"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7?r=557#message-557</id>
    <updated>2021-11-05T06:58:01-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>James West</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Nice to see you here! Thank you so much for posting this useful information, I really like it, so thanks for sharing it! But I advice you to click on this &lt;a href="https://handmadewriting.com/" class="external"&gt;handmadewriting.com&lt;/a&gt; writing company, where you can find needful help for you and buy assignments online. The prices are low at all learners subjects.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#65 Grid Certificate Profile : RE: Comments on Grid Certificate Profile</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7?r=511#message-511"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7?r=511#message-511</id>
    <updated>2019-09-02T00:26:15-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Roary Strickland</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I really needed this software and i like to say thanks to the person who have posted this here. Its a very useful thing and &lt;a href="https://www.dissertationhqhelp.com/edugeeksclub-com-review-9-10/" class="external"&gt;edugeeksclub&lt;/a&gt; also have wonderful collections of essays. There are so many ways to to find our required softwares for downloading on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#65 Grid Certificate Profile : Further comments on Grid Certificate Profile</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/8"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/8</id>
    <updated>2013-03-12T13:31:49-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>John Kewley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;[continuation of previous comments]&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;3.1 General Provisions states "... Note that modern hashes, such as SHA-256, are supported by the majority of OpenSSL versions in use, so SHA-2 is currently RECOMMENDED if the software in the entire community supports it. At least a  SHA-1 hash or stronger MUST be used." whereas 2.2 Serial Number [see my notes in previous Comment about the sectioning] states "... The current most secure hash function that is supported by the entire target audience of the CA SHOULD be used. In particular SHA-2 or better SHOULD be used and at least as strong as SHA-1 MUST be used". IMO they should be consistent (especially the bit about being supported by the entire target audience) if not identical.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.2.2 is described as "recommendations" and then makes statements like "SHOULD NOT" (fair enough) and "MUST NOT" (which is a prohibition not a recommendation)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;footnote 23 is attached to a "SHOULD NOT" yet it states "The quote characters must not be used". Although the "must not" is not in caps it seems strange to have a reason given for a "must not" when associated with a "SHOULD NOT" - should it be attached to the "MUST NOT" on the previous line? Or is some other interpretation intended?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;footnote 28, there are also reasons other than multiple projects for an individual to have more than one certificate: multiple roles (RA Operator maybe, in fact maybe an RA Operator for multiple RAs) and testing (key sizes, signature algorithms) are ones that spring to mine - maybe this could be generalised a bit&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;footnote 30 as this is an update to the document and globus 4.2 is some years old, maybe later versions of GT could be considered&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3 nsCertType vs extendedKeyUsage is contorted. extendedKeyUsage is "required" (see my my other set of comments) which implies compulsion / MUST, yet it needn't be present if nsCertType is present, but the latter is deprecated. 3.3.4 then states that nsCertType "MUST NOT" be used - this is all confusing (I get the gist, but feel is described clumsily and maybe it'd be better to state what should be the case for all new certificates and then give some allowances for existing ones, asserting whether they can be renewed in that state or not.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3 "includes also the extensions" -&gt; "also includes the extensions" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 36: "argumentation" is a word I have never seen in normal [UK] english usage (although my german-speaking colleagues in CH used to use it a lot). Can I suggest "justification" or "discussion" or "arguments" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 38 talks about "recent mail clients" - is this still untrue for the examples given?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 38 "other products" - "products" sounds strange - how about "tools" or "clients"?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 38 "reder" -&gt; "render" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3 the table spreads over 2 pages which makes it hard to read. The "Optional" section starts with a "," and has a double ",," in the middle&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3.4 "This extension is deprecated and it MUST NOT be used in new certificates, and the appropriate equivalent values be included in the&lt;br /&gt;         extendedKeyUsage extension" &lt;br /&gt;        -&gt;&lt;br /&gt;        "This extension is deprecated. It MUST NOT be used in new certificates: the appropriate equivalent values MUST/SHOULD be included in the&lt;br /&gt;         extendedKeyUsage extension" [probably a MUST, but I'll leave that to others to decide]&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;If nsCertType is present, does it matter whether it is marked as "critical" or not?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3.5 "If any of these is included" -&gt; "If any of these are included" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3.6 should there be something stronger than "is not required" like "SHOULD NOT be used"?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.3.7 "is known not to be able to handle" -&gt; "is known to be unable to handle" or maybe even avoid "hearsay" and just say "cannot handle" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 46 - what is "Chapter 5"? This document has a section 5, but I don't think it is relevant - if it is maybe more info is needed to point at the information hinted at.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;JK&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#65 Grid Certificate Profile : Comments on Grid Certificate Profile</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/7</id>
    <updated>2013-03-12T07:00:50-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>John Kewley</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
Overall
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;I find the ragged right layout awkward to read (or even a bit slap-dash) compared to the justified footnotes, but that is probably a personal preference.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;rfc 822 is mentioned a lot. It was obsoleted by rfc2822, which in turn was obsoleted by RFC 522&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Extensions tables. I believe there is some lack of clarity in these (e.g. in 2.4) for the following reasons:&lt;br /&gt;  1. The top section (Required) has values on separate lines, they should be merged like the other sections, or at least the separating line removed&lt;br /&gt;     if it is important for them to be on separate lines.&lt;br /&gt;  2. There isn't always a good match between the table category and the text below. I am assuming that "Required" =&gt; MUST, "Advised to use" =&gt; SHOULD,&lt;br /&gt;     "Optional" =&gt; "MAY" and "Not to be used" =&gt; "MUST NOT", but this isn't always the case. In particular some of the "Not to be used" is "SHOULD NOT".&lt;br /&gt;     (e.g. 2.4.3 extendedKeyUsage)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;"a priori" -&gt; use italics for latin&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;When we talk about extensions being critical or not, should we use italics for "critical"?&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


Section 1
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;"this should not be construed as to mean the extension or attribute is either useful or harmless" &lt;br /&gt;  I'd change "to mean" to "meaning".&lt;br /&gt;  Also each time I read it my brain tells me that it should say "useless" rather than "useful" - maybe it just sounds wrong juxtaposing&lt;br /&gt;  a positive with a negative like that.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


Section 2
	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The information on message digests appears under "Serial Number", maybe it should have its own subsection or be included under "General Provisions". In Section 3, MDs and SNs are described under this latter section.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.3 SETs are mentioned - I can't see a definition of this term before this point. I can see from the appendix that is part of the structure of an ASN.1 SEQUENCE, but maybe something is needed before this point.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 1: "for example in case only the lifetime is extended" -&gt; "for example in the case that the lifetime is extended" [meaning changes subtly from that of an unexpected occurrence to a potentially expected one]&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;In this same footnote IE7 is mentioned a few times - if we are re-issuing the document, should we not show we have tried with later versions of IE?&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 2: "Note that modern hashes, such as SHA-256, are supported in recent versions of the majority of software, such as OpenSSL in use, so SHA-1 is no longer the only available value as of time of writing." -&gt; Sentence is clumsy, maybe move comma from after "in use" to before. Basically there are too many commas so it is hard to see what is parenthesised and what isn't.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.3.1 "the CA the CN" -&gt; "the CA. The CN" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.3.3 "serialNumber {2.5.4.5}" - there is no description of what the numbers in curly braces represent; the other components don't have this designation in this section.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.3.4 "depricated" -&gt; "deprecated" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.3.4 Might it be better just to say emailAddress MUST NOT be used for CA certificates&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;AuthorityInfoAccess -&gt; authorityInfoAccess (for consistency)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.4.3 "It MUST NOT be marked critical" -&gt; "If present, it MUST NOT be marked critical" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 9 "life time" -&gt; "lifetime" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 9 - no definition/description of what an "indirect CRL" is, likewise for OCSP - maybe a link is needed.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;"There is also no direct way to create such an end-entity certificate in the many CA products" -&gt; "... in many CA products" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 14 "If adding explicit text to the certificate, such as was possible using the nsComment extension, is desired, the new attribute ..." -&gt;&lt;br /&gt;              "If adding explicit text to the certificate is desired, as was possible using the nsComment extension, then the appropriate attribute ..." &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.4.6 "The certificatePolicies extension may be set" -&gt; "... MAY be set" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.4.7 "The cRLDistributionPoints extension need not be in a self-signed root CA certificate" - I suggest changing "need not be" to use terms like "MAY" or "SHOULD" &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;2.4.8 "A subjectKeyIdentifier extension MUST be included in CA certificates to aid in validation path construction and&lt;br /&gt;         an authorityKeyIdentifier MUST be included in all CA certificates, unless the certificate is self-signed." &lt;br /&gt;        The problem here is that it isn't obvious what the scope is of the final "unless the certificate is self-signed" - is it whole sentence, or only the bit &lt;br /&gt;        after the "and".&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Footnote 19: "should" -&gt; "SHOULD"? &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;3.1 "by the same issuer" - it isn't clear from this what "same" means. Consider re-signed/extended certificates, re-keyed certificates, an offline and&lt;br /&gt;        an online CA signing in the same namespace. There are many possibilities. Does it mean "by the same issuer (i.e. with the same DN)"&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;[truncated - I have more comments on section 3 which I'll add later]&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;JK&lt;/p&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>#65 Grid Certificate Profile : Document is in public comment until May 10th, 2013</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/6"/>
    <id>https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/6</id>
    <updated>2013-03-10T20:30:25-04:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Redmine Admin</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
&lt;hr /&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document Links&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href="http://redmine.ogf.org/attachments/53/draft-ogf-caops-grid-certificate-profile-125bis-v06.pdf" class="external"&gt;[pdf]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://redmine.ogf.org/attachments/52/draft-ogf-caops-grid-certificate-profile-125bis-v06.doc" class="external"&gt;[doc]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://redmine.ogf.org/boards/8/topics/new" class="external"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comment Here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This document provides guidance for the use of directory names, attributes, and extensions in&lt;br /&gt;X.509 certificates, such that they are usable by the majority of the grid infrastructures today.&lt;br /&gt;The intended audience for this document includes issuers of X.509 certificates for use in grid&lt;br /&gt;infrastructures, and implementers of X.509 validation software for grid purposes.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Interoperability for X.509 identity certificates between the issuers of certificates and the&lt;br /&gt;software that interprets them is increasingly more important as the number of participants in&lt;br /&gt;grids that rely on a X.509 certificates grows. It is difficult to predict which particular software&lt;br /&gt;will be used by the parties relying on the certificate, and how this software interprets specific&lt;br /&gt;name forms, attributes, and extensions. This document gives guidance and defines explicit&lt;br /&gt;restrictions on the certificate profile to ensure the certificate is interpreted by the relying party&lt;br /&gt;in the way the issuer intended. It specifies and further restricts the certificate format as&lt;br /&gt;defined in RFC5280 and the X.509 standard.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This document extends the guidance in GFD.125 by specifying additional constraints and&lt;br /&gt;providing further clarification.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
