OGSA-WG phone conference minutes
================================

26 October 2006

Participants
============
Hiro Kishimoto, Fujitsu,
Michel Drescher, Fujitsu
Blair Dillaway, Microsoft
Allan Sill, TTU
Andrew Grimshaw, UoV
Andreas Savva, Fujitsu
Jem Treadwell, HP
Mike Behrens, R2DD
David Snelling, Fujitsu

Early Discussion
================
- Michel Drescher has been appointed to take minutes.
- Oct 23 telecon minutes have been approved without changes.
- Action Item review (only changed AI are listed here)
    -- AI-1023a: CLOSED
    -- AI-1023e: CLOSED
- Glossary discussion added to Oct 30 phone call

Nov F2F update (OGSA-16)
========================
- 14 participants expected so far
- proposed agenda not closed yet, time slot requests welcome

OGSA-AuthN WG charter discussion
================================
- Blair sent a response to the initial charter draft sent by Alan
    -- Alan is working on the this response
- Alan so far answered four of the famous "seven questions of GFSG"
- Alan presents the answers to the questions
    -- Andrew points out that when documenting current practices, an 
      outcome should be a set of recommendations
    -- The group discusses the potential list of output documents of
      this WG
    -- The group discusses whether it is in scope for this group to
      output a list of recommendations
    -- The group discusses the problem of delegation in secure Grid
      infrastructure
- Hiro asks for contribution of people to review the charter and 
  "7 questions"
- The group discusses the management and propotion of the OGSA-AuthN
  BoF towards broader audience
- D Snelling (as VP Standards) points out the different uses of the term
  "Recommendation" as part of
    -- a specification document
       Giving specific information of what must be implemented
    -- a community practice document
       Giving information about what has been used so far (and what 
       hs proven good to use wnd what did not)
    -- a roadmap document
       Outlining the direction AuthN should go in Grids
- The group discusses the general direction the OGSA-AuthN WG should go
- The group discusses the next steps to undertake to get OGSA-AuthN through 
  the OGF process

Misc. Security discussion
-------------------------
- Andrew expresses his concerns about the OGF Security area
    -- Andrew expresses that not only the current set of known and used
       technology should be tackledd, but also
    -- the "next round" of challenges and technologies that should or might
       be used in the future
- Michael Behrens raises Globus proxy certs as an issue to explore further 
  in AuthN and AuthZ
    -- Alan Sill points out that this technology, while being useful and 
       popular, exposes the threat of complete anonymisation of services
       as users are able to create localised CAs.
    -- Alan also points out 

WRAP UP 
=======
- Next call coming Monday, Oct 30
